Mykhailo Rybintsev

Pembrokeshire, UK, SA69 · +447771484577

michael.rybintsev@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/mykhailo-rybintsev

Software Engineer

Highly skilled engineer with experience and success in all aspects of systems design and development in a fast-paced, rapidly changing environment. Well-versed in a wide array of platforms, software, and languages as well as trouble-shooting skills and root cause analyses.

Respected as a valued partner, quick learner, and passionate team-player with strong collaborative skills who maintains keen awareness of the "big picture", emphasizing quality achievement, operational efficiency, and productivity.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Technical Skills

- Node (JS/TS), React, NextJS, Redux, SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL, MSSQL Server, Prisma), Git/GitHub, C#, .NET, Go.
- Cloud Providers: AWS, GCP, Azure; Scrum, Kanban, et al.

Professional Experience

Control Plane Ltd. London, UK

Cloud Native Engineer (April 2021 - Current)

- Took an MVP internal project to market.
- Refactored the most critical parts and made the product ready for on-boarding of outsourcing companies to help build features.
- Designed UI/UX, implemented multiple product features using NextJS.
- Refactored Node and Python backend services, adding and/or increasing test coverage.
- Created project documentation with best practices, introduced linting.
- Handled all aspects of the product, from source and integrations with AuthO and Stripe, CI/CD pipelines, to deployment on GCP with Cloud Run and GKE.
- Took active part in product discussions, feature prioritisation and updated stakeholders with status updates on the progress.

Huddle, London, UK

Delivery Manager/Developer (January 2019 - March 2021)

- Build RESTful APIs using continuous integration and continuous delivery best practices, version control, and Test-Driven-Development.
- Designed, developed, and implemented a lambda function with intelligence to power down unused development infrastructure, saving an estimated £10k annually in operating cost.
- Facilitate company-wide training and workshops, developing advanced skills in internal tooling and using API services, resulting in increased engineering staff productivity.
- Create demonstrations, providing clients with visuals to better understand new solutions functionality, features, controls, data analytics, and reporting.
- Introduced modifications to daily stand-up meeting agendas, building efficiency in knowledge transfer, and reducing meeting duration.
- Formulated GitHub checklists and comprehensive documentation practices, efficiently creating a high degree of discipline to ensure accuracy and quality during development.

Mykhailo Rybintsev

Page Two

- Orchestrate activities and timelines across project resources with being sensitive to not over-allocate resources and ensuring on-time and within-budget delivery.
- Partner with cross-functional teams ensuring internal systems are delivered with stability, reliability, and efficiency as well as providing Production Support knowledge transfer.
- Infuse Agile methodologies and DevOps discipline throughout the systems development lifecycle to ensure high levels of use of effective practices.
- Coach and mentor junior staff members to strengthen development team skill sets.

HT2 Labs, Oxford, UK

Software Engineer (August 2018 - January 2019)

- Built features for a brand new product, ensuring valuable client functionality as well as ease of code maintainability and sustainability.
- Created and facilitated client demos, featuring the value and effectiveness of system controls and capabilities.
- Created TypeScript learning sessions to introduce best practices to the development teams.
- Coordinated efforts with tech leads and backend engineers to ensure well-orchestrated practices and disciplined environment.

New Orbit Ltd, Oxford, UK

Junior Web Developer (October 2017 - August 2018)

- Absorbed and retained knowledge while coding and fixing bugs.
- Strategized with the UI/UX team to ensure valuable and effective user experience.
- Designed a view to embed Microsoft PowerBI dashboard into the admin page, enabling customers to view business performance statistics.
- Wrote several internal integrations using Slack and GitHub and continuous integration and continuous delivery automation, creating a streamlined functional process.

WFT Ltd, Eastbourne, UK

Mechanical Design Engineer (June 2016 - September 2017)

Developed Python jig with Raspberry Pi, Arduino, sensors, and a 3D printer to
continuously run equipment for 1000 hours in order to detect overnight leaks and send
an automated email to the engineering team with a timestamped log outlining the entire
test run results.

Volunteered, helping foster interest in the developer profession, at:

- freeCodeCamp Oxford
- CodeFirst Girls
- Code Club

Education

Dnipropetrovsk National University,

Bachelor's Degree in Engineering Mechanics, Aircraft and Rocket Engineering